So, what do you do when you lack
motivation
in your business? Motivation can be
fleeting. It can be here one second and
gone the next. And here's what I found
is the best thing to do is some days I
don't feel like getting up and building
my business and doing the stuff that I
want to do. And so, what I've learned is
that when those moments happen, the best
thing that I can do is learn to
cultivate the motivation. This goes
beyond just discipline. We hear people
say be disciplined. Do it even when
you're scared. Do it when you don't want
to. But sometimes, you know, like when
it comes to creating video content or
things like this, the your the energy
that you show up with it in matters. The
energy that I show up to make a video
like this matters. And so sometimes I
don't feel motivated to make a great
video. And those videos kind of stink
when I put them out there. When I create
ads that don't have the right energy,
they kind of stink when I put them out
there. How do I build up that
motivation? It's not necessarily
motivation that I build up, but what I
do is I take some time
to think in my mind about the outcome
that I want and why am I doing this and
reminding myself of why I got started. I
remind myself of all the winds that I've
had and I build up inside of myself an
internal temperature dialogue and
environment in my thinking that keeps me
aligned with the goals, vision, and
ideas that I have. And so what that does
is it keeps me
from letting how I feel affect what's
happening. I I have great days and I
have days where I just literally don't
feel motivated to show up in my
business, but I do show up every single
day. Not because I have a boss that's
over my head or says I have to do it.
Because as an entrepreneur, you don't
have those bosses. You don't have
somebody that's telling you you have to
do this. You might have your bills that
are telling you that. But beyond your
bills, like what is motivating you? not
wanting to go bankrupt might be
motivating you, but beyond that, that's
not really a great motivator. So, you
got to grab a vision for something that
is bigger than just yourself. It's
bigger than just what are people going
to think about me. It's about what is
the impact that this is going to have.
So, I always think about what is the
impact that me making this video going
to have on people that I'm reaching
online. What kind of impact is this
going to have on people's lives that I
want it to affect them? And then I think
about what can I do that can help
somebody today? What is something as
well that I'm not bored of talking about
all the time? This is another thing that
I'll do if I'm lacking motivation. I'll
think about what's a topic that I love
to talk about all the time. What's
something that I enjoy doing? And what
this will do is this will fire off the
dopamine inside of me to get me more
excited to do those things. So sometimes
if I'm lacking motivation, what I will
actually do is I say, "Okay, I have to
do these 10 things over here. let me
actually pick the one thing that I
really want to do and that will help me
gain the ability to do that. Have you
ever heard the the term eat the frog? Do
the hardest thing first. That is good to
do on a regular basis. But when you are
not feeling in it, you're not feeling
excited. You're feeling a bit drained.
You're feeling kind of tired.
One of the things that I like to do is
instead I flip it and I do the thing
that I really want to do more than
anything else to motivate me to gain the
motivation to then do those other
things. At the end of the day though,
you're responsible for how you show up
in your business, what you do, and what
you're willing to
put aside. Make sure that you prioritize
what's important. Prioritize what is
going to be profit producing in your
business. I want you to think about,
okay, what are the activities that I
need to do that are going to produce a
profit for my business, not just busy
work that feels like you're doing stuff
in your business. I talk with people all
the time. I coach them and they say,
"Jeremiah, sometimes I just doesn't feel
fun for me to build my business." And
that's the thing. It's not always going
to feel fun. It's not always going to be
something that you're just like, "Oh my
gosh, it just lights me on fire to do
these types of things." making videos
like this. I do them all the time. It
actually does light me on fire to do
that. But sometimes I just don't want to
make a video. Sometimes I just don't
want to record. Sometimes I just want to
sit around and watch Netflix or play
video games. And what I got to do is I
got to say, nope. You know what? I'm
going to put that aside
and I'm going to start to imagine and
visualize in my head, who are the people
that I'm impacting? Who are the people
that need to hear the message that I'm
talking about? who are the people that I
know that are going to benefit from this
the most and I get a vision in my mind
of those people. I start thinking about
them. I start thinking about what is the
message that I know can help them the
most. If I'm really struggling with this
as well, here's something that I did. Uh
chat GBT has this voice mode where you
can talk with the AI and I told it, hey,
listen, I want to come up with some
ideas for video content to create. can
you interview me about what I could talk
about with my clients to help me
brainstorm ideas? And literally the AI
that'll talk back to you in chat GBT
started asking me questions that gave me
ideas for two or three pieces of
content. It's incredible. And these are
some great things that you can do. So,
if you're lacking motivation, a couple
of things that I love to do is I'll
either go distract myself and do
something real quick that I've been
wanting to do. I'll do something in my
business that I've been wanting to do
for a while or then what I will do is I
can also dialogue with AI and ask it to
give me ideas and usually nine times out
of 10 I will start to have that
motivation. If I'm still struggling with
that, you know what I'll do? I will go
for a walk or I'll go take a shower or
I'll go eat some food. Sometimes I'm
just tired because my blood sugar is
low. I will go um play with my kids for
a little bit. I'll go do a chore that
I've been putting off. And so what these
things are is these are again quick wins
that I can do in my life that then gives
me the motivation. It starts triggering
in my brain ideas for what I could be
doing in my business. And this happens
all the time for me is is what I do as
an entrepreneur that works at home
sometimes. Listen, what's more
productive for me to do? sit on the
couch, sit on front of my computer,
scroll social media, hoping to gain
motivation, or getting up from the
computer, running the vacuum for a
little bit, and then getting an idea for
a video and then sitting down to record
that video. I'll tell you the answer.
It's not scrolling social media. It's
not sitting on the couch hoping to get
some motivation.
It's going to do the thing. I'm going to
go make some lunch. I'm going to go take
a take a shower. I'm going to go do do
something like that. And those things I
I say take a shower because sometimes I
don't like right away in the morning or
sometimes I do at night and sometimes I
might take two showers in a day to
motivate me. Anyways, don't need that
visual. I'm joking some y'all. But like
with that, it's like I don't worry about
getting it perfect or sticking to like,
okay, I have to do this right now is my
working time and so I got to sit down
and do that working time right here. No,
I play around with in my mind
what
is going to get me into the right state
of mind to where I'm going to be able to
show up at a high level for my clients.
Do I'm going to be able to show up at
the level that they expect to I'm going
to be able to show up and create content
that people are absolutely going to
love. And when I do that,
everything works out 10 times better. I
get out of my head, out of my own way,
out of trying to protect myself of what
everybody's going to think about me
and it just flows for me and I get into
a flow state. A flow state is a state of
mind where everything is just flowing
easily. It's coming easily and I'm able
to share these thoughts and these ideas
and I'm not secondguessing them as I'm
sharing them. I'm putting them out
there. I'm getting them into the public
sphere and it's creating the impact that
I want. And my friends, if you can do
this, if you can create a lifestyle of
that in your life and in your business,
it will help you far greater than you
ever could imagine. Listen, if you're a
mentor or a coach and you want to get
more clients in your business, I'd love
to work with you in the Wealthy Coach
Academy program. I'd love to see what's
it going to take for you to go to the
next level in your life, in your
business, to get the results that you
want. and I'd love to help you by coming
alongside you to help you build that
with you. We have a trial of our Wealthy
Coach Academy program. You can try it
out for 14 days and work with me to help
you get those results. We'll talk soon
everybody. Have a good one.